Hello friends, welcome to the site.
Today we are going to talk about when we purchase a health
insurance policy and the
details that we submit to the
insurance company, then by mistake
some details are given wrong and when we submit those details to the
insurance company for any claim
or to the hospital, then the
insurance company catches hold of
this and creates an issue and
rejects the claim by repeatedly citing this reason in this clause and every
time it does the same thing again and again whenever you need to process the claim, it
rejects the claim
but it is
not your fault, it is because of giving wrong details in the beginning
or sending wrong details, because of the agent or the
online portals,
you have to face this problem, so
what can you do in that condition, I am going to
tell you in this video, so let's
start the video, if you are new to the channel
then do subscribe to the channel.
[Music]
While purchasing health insurance, it is
very important for us to take care of many buttons,
we have to read everything in it in detail.  It
happens and you have to know it in detail,
whether it is from the agent or
from your online portal where you are purchasing.
Only after thorough investigation and getting complete information, we should purchase a plan or
a policy.
After providing some wrong details, the insurance
company catches hold of those things and issues arise
when they have to pass the claim. So
we have to take care of these things right from the beginning. There are
many reasons for
which the
insurance company becomes an issue. There are
some of those things which I am going to tell you
and you can back off from these things. Whenever you
purchase a plan from an insurance company
and that insurance company
finds some reason or the other due to which
your claim gets rejected and due to
which you have to
spend money. [Sangeet] Sanjeev. You have already
paid the premium to the insurance company, but
even after that you have to spend your money, it is
very sad when you have to spend your money on this
thing. There is another option for that
which you can use within your policy. Just
like we port our SIM,
similarly we can port the health insurance company to
another company.  You can port
your health policy
to another insurance company.
What happens in it is like
how is the network in our mobile SIM
or the net is not working, whatever problem happens
or there is a problem with many other plans etc.
So what we do is we
port that SIM from that company to another company, then the
number is changed to SIM
and we start getting the service of that other company.
We
can do the same in a health insurance company.
What will happen is that first of all we have to compare the
policy that we have purchased earlier and the second
policy or the policy of the other company that we are going to
purchase. We have to find out whether
this plan will be
best for us as per our facilities and will be
best for our family. So
this thing has to be researched first. After that, whether
you have to purchase this policy from an online portal
or from an agent,
we have to discuss this in advance
and by talking to customer care
or by doing complete research,
first you have to find out which plan is currently running in your health insurance company and
After comparing the plans of the insurance company you are purchasing, you have to decide
that we want to purchase this plan.
After that, we have to submit
our policy
and our ID etc. through Urgent or online portal.
After one or two or three days, the policy gets ported, due to
which your old company's benefits are also
added to it and you
can avail those benefits as well. So, you have to clear this thing in advance
that what benefits are we going to get, what
benefits of the old
company will be added to it or not,
or what will be the premium, it should not happen
that the premium is higher than the old company
and you do not get the old benefits in it.
What does the old benefit mean,
like we have been with an insurance company for one
year. It has been one year since our
old policy, then after one year,
what facilities would have been added to us, then we have to
find out first whether the next company will add that SIM facility to us or not.
And the second thing is that whenever
we get a health insurance policy,  When we port a policy, when the
policy's time is about to
expire, we have to do all this research 15 days
before, 20 days before, one month before so that
we do not face any
last minute problem. So in today's
video, I have told you about
porting a health insurance policy, so please
like this video and share it with your friends. If you have
any questions regarding this, then
please write to me in the comment section. We will meet
in the next video, till then,
goodbye.